Alfred H. Barr, Jr. Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - AHB Correspondence A-M, 1943; American British Art Center (Story, Mrs., Ala) A. C. A. Gallery (Baron, Herman; incl. ALS, TLS; Egan, Charles) Balmori, Santos Berdeau, Le Ray M/M (Society for the Arts; incl. ALS, 5 TLS, corresp. re: Latin-American Exhibition: Princess Gourielli; Lyford, Olive; Coordinator of Inter American Affairs) Berman, Genia (incl. JTS TLS) Berman, Sarah Bing, A. M. Boston (Museum of Fine Arts; Constable, W. G.; Dwyer, Darthea Field; Edgall, G. H. incl. TLS) Brenner, Anita (incl. 3 TLS) Blume, Peter (correp. re.) Bucher, Mrs., G. C. (incl. ALS) Buchholz Gallery (Valentin, Curt; incl. TLS) Calder, Alexander (incl. 3 ALS) Callery, Meric (incl. 2 ALS) Canade, Vincent (corresp. re.) Chadwick, Mrs., E. G. Cleveland Museum of Art, The (Francis, Henry Styles) Crowninshield, Frank (incl. 2 ALS) Davenport, Mrs., Walter Davis, Bernard (La France Industries; incl. TLS, corresp. re: Tchelitchew's Fallen Clown) Davis, Stewart (incl. ALS) Del Prado, Maria Nunez De Rocco, Jovan (Sweet Briar College; incl. ALS, corresp. re: complaint of Albright painting And God Created Man in His Image) Delavnay, Robert (ALS) Devoe, Ralph G. Dietrich, Dominian Gallery of Fine Art, The (Stern, Max) Dreier, Katherine (incl. 2 JTS TLS) Duchamp, Marcel Durand-Ruel, Inc. (Elfers, Herbert H.) Duveen Brothers (Lowengard, Armand; incl. TLS) Egas, Camilo Fogg Museum of Art; Harvard University (Sachs, Paul J.) Flato, Hans (incl. TLS) Graves, H. G. (incl. 2 ALS) Hamar, Irene Hare, Meredith Hewitt, Edwin (TL re: Castellanos's St. John's Day) High School of Music and Art (Steigman, Benjamin) Howard, Thomas Fine Hugo, Ian (incl. TLS, 3 ALS) Jansen, Roy (incl. 4 TLS) Koehnline, William Kootz, Samuel Katz, Leo La Quinta Gallery (Haugland Willard) Lamont, David Lejeune, H. Levine, Jack Lewis, Wyndham Lewisohn, Samuel A. Lilienfeld, Karl McAlpin, David McKinley, Charles Martins, Mrs., Carlos (Brazilian Embassy; incl. ALS) Merrill, Charles E. Munk, Peter Muller (Carnegie Institute) Moncayo Moselio, Simon (Bennington College) Museum of Modern Art (incl. memos re: de Chirico, Maxim Kopf, Acquisitions Committee, Tamayo,Museum Collection Accessions Book, recent poster acquistions, Andre Racz) File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.[3] mf 2199:785)
  - AHB Correspondence N-Z, 1943; National Gallery of Art (Finley, David E.; Walker, John) Neumann, J. B. (incl. ALS) Ochs, E. Passedoit, Georgette (Passedoit Gallery; incl. TLS) Pereira, Irene Philadelphia Museum of Art (Clifford, Henry; incl. 7 TLS, ALS; Kimball, Fiskel; incl. TLS; Marceau, Henri; incl. TLS) Picasso, Pablo (memo re:Guernica) Picken, George Poter, Mrs., Nathan Todd Porter, Elliot Poore, Charles M/M Puma, Fernando (Puma Gallery; incl. 7 TLS) Quirt, Walter (incl. ALS) Reder, Bernard (incl. ALS) Reder, Mrs., Stanley (J. W. Thompson Gallery) Rhode Island School of Design (Shwartz, Heinrich) Rockefeller, Nelson A. (incl. TLS) Rogers, Charles Bolles (incl. TLS) Rosenberg, Paul Saber, Clifford Schiefer, Johannes Scudder, Mrs., Wallace M. (Artists of Today) Seligmann, Germain Siqueriros, David Alfaro Smith College Museum of Art, The (Abbott, Jere; incl. 3 TLS) Spitzer, Julius Strand, Paul Sweeny, James Johnson Tamayo, Rufino Thompson, Dorothy Toledo Museum of Art, The (Godwin, Blake-More; incl. 10 TLS) File incl. AHB ALS (Box 1, Folder 1.[4] mf 2199:1079)
  - MoMA: Exhibitions: Schedules & lists, 1942; Wheeler, Monroe (Box 1, Folder 1.[5] mf 2199:1206)
  - MoMA: Photography Committee, 1943-1945; File incl. memo re: McAlpin talks in photographic project, report of the Picture Use Sub-Committee of the Advisory Council 1945 March 12 Minutes of the Advisory Committee on Photography meeting: 1945 January 4 1944 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 1.[6] mf 2199:1227)
  - Policy Committee, 1944; Courter, Elodie Moe, Henry Allen (incl. 2 TLS) File incl. Report on the Policy Committee on Circulating Exhibitions 1944 July 26, report of the Officer of Assistant Treasurer and Controller, report of the Front Desk, brief definition of the work of the Department of Painting and Sculpture, 1944 June Library Report (Box 1, Folder 1.[7] mf 2199:1249)
  - MoMA:Life Article, 1950; File incl. information requested from Life for museum story (Dorothy Seiberling) Identification of works in the collection of MoMA show in Life Photograph List of Dorothy Seiberling's questions re:Life Article Attendance figures 1929-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1.[8] mf 2199:1302)
- Series 1b: Barr Biographical: Honors and Awards
  Given to MoMA Library for Alfred Barr Archive by Mrs. Alfred Barr July 8 and June 9 1975. See also, folders #396-416 for related correspondence.
  - Subseries 1b.A. Awards (Plaques and Medals)
    - Framed Irish proverb/verse, 1967; From "Men" of MoMA production staff upon AHB's retirement (Box a, Folder 1b.A.1)
    - Brandeis University Creative Arts Award, 1965; Bronze round plaque in blue leather case (Box a, Folder 1b.A.2)
    - Art in America Annual Award, 1962; Bronze medal (Box a, Folder 1b.A.3)
    - Merit Award from Philadelphia College of Art, 6/1960 (Box a, Folder 1b.A.4)
    - Ordre de Chevalerie, Paris, Medal, white enamel star on green silver-leaf, with red ribbon Inner disc (blue and gold) marked:Republique Francaise, Honneur et Patrie Received in green felt jewelry case marked Shreve Crump & Low Co., Boston (Box a, Folder 1b.A.5)
    - Lgion d'Honneur, n.d., 1959; Tiny medal, looks like a miniature of no. 5 above Same colors, red ribbon, and wording as on disc above In small maroon leather box Received in same green felt jewelry case as above (Box a, Folder 1b.A.6)
    - Italian Medal, 1948; Gold star and medallion [red, green, and white ribbon] Lapel button In green leather box, with gold seal Jeweler: Cravanzola, Rome (Box a, Folder 1b.A.7)
  - Subseries 1b.B. Certificates
    - European Art Dealers' Association, 10/1948; Citation in Gerrrani envelope w. MSB's notes (Box b, Folder 1b.B.1)
    - Art Dealers Association of America Award for excellence in Art History, 4/20/1972 (Box b, Folder 1b.B.2)
    - Columbia University commencement program, 6/3/1969; At which AHB received Doctor of Human letters degree See Folio for degree, which is oversized (Box b, Folder 1b.B.3)
    - Society for the Arts, Religion and Contemporary Culture: Certificate of Appreciation, 2/22/1969 (Box b, Folder 1b.B.4)
    - Award for Distinguished Service to the Arts, 1968; Conferred by American Academy of Arts and letters and National Institute of Arts and letters Incl. award certificate Glenway Westcott's remarks AHB's handwritten reply (Box b, Folder 1b.B.5)
    - Yale University: Doctor of Fine Arts, 1967; Degree Program Clippings (Box b, Folder 1b.B.6)
    - New York State Award, 5/7/1968; Incl. program (Box b, Folder 1b.B.7)
    - Copy of New College Citation of Esteem, 5/3/1966; With AHB annotation (Box b, Folder 1b.B.8)
    - Brandeis University, 1964?; Certificate accompanying a medal for notable creative achievement (Box b, Folder 1b.B.9)
    - Photo: Columbia University 1963 degree recipients, AHB's Doctor of Humane letters degree in oversize folio (Box b, Folder 1b.B.10)
    - University of Buffalo Doctor of Fine Arts, 1962 (Box b, Folder 1b.B.11)
    - Italian Solidarity Award, 3/3/1961; Mrs. Barr refers to this as Italian Cavaliere (Box b, Folder 1b.B.12)
    - Bonn, Gennan degree "Das grosse Verdierstkreuz", 1959; Grand Order of Merit (Box b, Folder 1b.B.13)
    - AFA 50th Anniversary Award, 4/24/1959 (Box b, Folder 1b.B.13a)
    - Princeton: Doctor of Letters, 1949; Program 5 items incl. 2 letters Note from AHB to his mother Clippings (Box b, Folder 1b.B.14)
    - Lord & Taylor annual American Design Award ... for awakening in America an appreciation and recognition of modern art, 1947; Folder with 7 items (Box b, Folder 1b.B.15)
    - Students Army Training Corps of Princeton certificate, 12/4/1918 (Box b, Folder 1b.B.16)
    - Jefferson Avenue Presbyterian Bible School certificate, 6/28/1908 (Box b, Folder 1b.B.17)
  - Subseries 1b.C. Oversized Certificates
    - Columbia University: Doctor of Humane Letters, 1969 (Box c, Folder 1b.C.1)
    - Award of Merit from AIA, 1964 (Box c, Folder 1b.C.2)
    - Lgion d'Honneur, France, 1959; With letter from ? (Box c, Folder 1b.C.3)
    - Princeton: Doctor of Letters, 1959 (Box c, Folder 1b.C.4)
    - University of Bonn: Doctor of Philosophy, 1958; (MCMLVIII) (Box c, Folder 1b.C.5)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1962 (Box c, Folder 1b.C.6)
    - Harvard: PhD, 1946 (Box c, Folder 1b.C.7)
    - Princeton: B.A., 1922 (Box c, Folder 1b.C.8)
- Series 1c: Correspondence from Mrs. Stanley B. Resor
  - Correspondence from Mrs. Stanley B. Resor, 1934-1966; 165 items, including 4 photographs. Not filmed. 2.5" gray box (Box 1c.1)
- Series 2: Tributes and Condolences, 1981, 1983
  Barr died August 15, 1981; a memorial ceremony was held at MoMA, October 15, 1981; Tribute brochure was published 1983.
  - Tribute Booklet: Comments and corrections, ca. 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2.1.a mf 3145:4)
  - Tribute Booklet: Photos used in Tribute booklet, ca. 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2.1.b)
  - Tribute Booklet: Transcripts of ceremony, ca. 1981-1983; P. Johnson's copy of his speech (Box 1, Folder 2.1.c)
  - Obituaries (published), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2.2 mf 3145:152)
  - Private (Personal) Condolences: A - L, ca. 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2.3.a mf 3145:270)
  - Private Condolences: M - Z, ca. 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2.3.b mf 3145:504)
- Series 2a: Tributes, 1962, 1972 and undated
  Barr's 60th and 70th Birthdays were celebrated in 1962 and 1972; this material has not been microfilmed; Gift of Victoria Barr 1/8/92.
  - Tributes 1962: 60th Birthday, A - M, ca. 1962, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2a.1.a)
  - Tributes 1962: 60th Birthday, O - Z, ca. 1962, 1972; List of people sending AHB Birthday Messages List is not complete (Box 1, Folder 2a.1.b)
  - Tributes 1972: 70th Birthday, A - L, ca. 1962, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2a.2.a)
  - Tributes 1972: 70th Birthday, M - Z, ca. 1962, 1972; List of acceptances to Birthday Party (Box 1, Folder 2a.2.b)
  - Tributes Undated: Birthday Messages, ca. 1962, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2a.3)
  - Other, ca. 1962, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2a.4)
- Series 3: Abstract Art, Cubism, and Futurism, ca. 1910-1973
  Four 5" and one 2.5" document boxes of catalogs, clippings, announcements and other material collected by Barr in addition to related Barr correspondence. Each of the following five subseries include folders which in many instances are labeled in Barr's hand (designated below by quotation marks). Original order was maintained whenever feasible.
  - Subseries A: General Subjects, ca. 1930-1973
    - "American - early modern", 7 pages of AHB pencil notes on yellow paper 1 item (Box 1, Folder 3.A.1 mf 3145:1011)
    - Archipenko, 1936-1945; ca. 65 items Correspondence, photographs, printed mattter including announcements Could be considered sensitive, however, artist's widow wishes all details of his life and career to be made known (Box 1, Folder 3.A.2 mf 3145:1019)
    - "Architecture", 1944; 2 items Printed matter (Box 1, Folder 3.A.3 mf 3145:1128)
    - "Arp", 2 items Announcements (Box 1, Folder 3.A.4 mf 3145:1143)
    - "Biomorphic abstractions", 1946, n.d.; 1 item Printed matter (Box 1, Folder 3.A.5 mf 3145:1152)
    - "Czanne", 4 items 1 photo from Bernheim Jeune (Box 1, Folder 3.A.6 mf 3145:1162)
    - "Delauney", ca. 37 items (Box 1, Folder 3.A.7 mf 3145:1164)
    - van Doesburg, ca. 34 photos, 12 with Theo van Doesburg's annotations de Stijl, Jan. 1932 1 postcard 1 letter incl. 1 Vantangerloo photo (Box 1, Folder 3.A.8 mf 3145:1170)
    - "Duchamp", AHB's penciled notes of his interview with Duchamp 12/21/45 Copy of Yale Bulletin, March '45 (Box 1, Folder 3.A.9.a mf 3145:1279)
    - "Duchamp" Duchamp/Sweeney material, 1946; Re: Stettheimer exh. Duchamp's visa problems See also 1.273 ca. 36 items (Box 1, Folder 3.A.9.b mf 3145:1291)
    - "les Fauves", 1941; 1 catalog, Harriman Gallery (Box 1, Folder 3.A.10 mf 3145:1335)
    - "Film" (Box 1, Folder 3.A.11 mf 3145:1341)
    - "Glarner", 1949; 4 photos Gallery announcement (Box 1, Folder 3.A.12 mf 3145:1346)
    - Hitchcock, Henry Russell, 1930, 1935, 1937; Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3.A.13 mf 3145:1358-1381 mf 3146:6-31)
    - "Philip Johnson", 2 items (Box 1, Folder 3.A.14 mf 3146:32)
    - "Kandinsky", 1936, 1946, 1958; 6 items Incl. 1946 note from Mme. Kandinsky 1936 notes from the artist (Box 1, Folder 3.A.15 mf 3146:36)
    - "Kupka", 50 items Incl. notes, color transparencies, b/w photographs An orig. [?] Kupka pencil sketch, etc. (Box 1, Folder 3.A.16 mf 3146:80)
    - "Lewis, Wynd." [Wyndham], 2 items 1940 'New Republic' articles See also, 3.B.4 (Box 1, Folder 3.A.17 mf 3146:188)
    - "Machinism", 5 items (Box 1, Folder 3.A.18 mf 3146:194)
    - Malevich: Correspondence and info, ca. 1967-1973; 23 items (Box 1, Folder 3.A.19.a mf 3146:208)
    - Malevich: Correspondence and info, ca. 1967-1972; 8 items (Box 1, Folder 3.A.19.b mf 3146:208)
    - Malevich: Nadejena Correspondence, 55 items (Box 1, Folder 3.A.19.c mf 3146:208)
    - "Mathematics", 2 items 1945 exhange between AHB and Blake re: latter's researches into geometry of design (Box 1, Folder 3.A.20 mf 3146:248)
    - "Mir", 2 items 2 n.d. announcements from Pierre Matisse Gallery re: Mir's Farm (Box 1, Folder 3.A.21 mf 3146:261)
    - "Moholy-N." (Moholy-Nagy), 2 items 1939 letter to AHB and AHB's notes from Vision in Motion (Box 1, Folder 3.A.22 mf 3146:266)
    - "Paalen", 7 items Photographs and 11945 Art of This Century Gallery announcement (Box 2, Folder 3.A.23 mf 3146:272)
    - "Pevsner" [Antoine], 1 item A brief chronology (1888-1926) of Pevsner perhaps by the artist Not signed (Box 2, Folder 3.A.24 mf 3146:291)
    - "Primitivism", 5 items Incl. 2 pgs. of AHB's notes "Attitude towards Primitive Art" (Box 2, Folder 3.A.25 mf 3146:295)
    - "Proto-abstract", 4 items 3 photographs 1 ill. (Box 2, Folder 3.A.26 mf 3146:309)
    - Richter, Hans: Correpsondence, 1943, 1950; 4 items (Box 2, Folder 3.A.27 mf 3146:316)
    - "Rorschach", 11 items 10 dwgs. and 1 pg. notes 4 basic themes repeated (Box 2, Folder 3.A.28 mf 3146:322)
    - Schmidt-Rottluff, 16 items Incl. 2 1928 letters to AHB at Wellesley (Box 2, Folder 3.A.29 mf 3146:325)
    - "Science and art", 4 items (Box 2, Folder 3.A.30 mf 3146:370)
    - "de Stijl", 5 items 1 memo of 1960 Letter and printed matter See also, AHB Articles (Box 2, Folder 3.A.31 mf 3146:393)
    - "Synchromism", 1 item 1 pg. of AHB's notes perhaps from Willard Huntington Wright's Modern Painting, its tendency and meaning, NY: John Lane, 1915. per rr (Box 2, Folder 3.A.32 mf 3146:415)
    - "Wright, F.L.", 2 items FLW letter in reply to AHB's which is missing from this folder (Box 2, Folder 3.A.33 mf 3146:418)
  - Subseries B: Abstract Art, ca. 1917-1965
    - Printed Matter, ca. 1949-1965; 27 items Incl. clippings, gallery announcements, copies of letters and notes (Box 2, Folder 3.B.1 mf 3146:431)
    - Catalogs, ca. 1917-1955; 5 items. NORD-SUO, 15 Mai 1917, with Pierre Reverdy's "Sur le Cubisme" is the early item (Box 2, Folder 3.B.2 mf 3146:512)
    - "Analogues", 2 items Incl. MSB's handwritten notes (Box 2, Folder 3.B.3 mf 3146:732)
    - "Theory", 7 items All printed matter Incl. 1923 May and 4 articles from 1940 issues of Chapbook New Republic (Box 2, Folder 3.B.4 mf 3146:740)
  - Subseries C: Cubism and Abstract Art, ca. 1933-1940
    - Post-Publication Material, ca. 1940; 15 items Printed matter Correspondence incl. letters from Burliuk, Louise Bourgeois AHB's notes June '58 on origin of term suprematism (Box 3, Folder 3.C.1 mf 3146:764)
    - Barr Notes: 1949 notes, ca. 30 sheets Typed and handwritten (Box 3, Folder 3.C.2.a mf 3146:813)
    - Barr Notes: "Notes for Cubism book", 1 item 45+ yellow penciled sheets of AHB's notes Original order strictly maintained (Box 3, Folder 3.C.2.b mf 3146:847)
    - Dummy, 1937; 1 item Colophon page reads "Second edition, June 1937" in DCM's handwriting Typed note affixed to endsheet opposite cover reads " ... this is the dummy for a corrected edition of the book. Only copy! /s/ D. Miller." (Box 3, Folder 3.C.3 mf 3146:879)
    - Chart clippings etc., 7 items Items found in KEY copy of cat. (Box 3, Folder 3.C.4a mf 3146:1025)
    - Clippings, 1936; 10 items Re: book and exhibition (Box 3, Folder 3.C.5 mf 3146:1043)
    - Publication Details: Catalog Page Proof, 2 copies, each 39 pgs. One annotated (Box 3, Folder 3.C.6.a mf 3146:1073)
    - Publication Details: Acknowledgments (Box 3, Folder 3.C.6.b mf 3146:1136)
    - Publication Details: Production Information Cuts Available (Box 3, Folder 3.C.6.c.i mf 3146:1140)
    - Publication Details: Production Information Book Schedule (Box 3, Folder 3.C.6.c.ii mf 3146:1143)
    - Typescript for Book, 2 items 129 typed pgs. and carbons (Box 3, Folder 3.C.7 mf 3146:1145-1233)
    - Correspondence re: Book, 1936; 24 items Incl. letters from Herbin, Kupka, Leyda, Lonce Rosenberg Diagram from/by Calder of Rietveld chair lent to the exh. (Box 3, Folder 3.C.8 mf 3147:59)
    - Exhibition Details, ca. 1933-1936; 18 items Early details and plans AHB handwritten charts [n.d.] and "isms" List [1927] Lists of works of art, collectors Typed report [n.d.] of Trustee Advisory Comm. referring to an exh.Towards Abstraction (Box 3, Folder 3.C.9 mf 3147:92)
    - Two AHB Marked Copies of Catalog with Inserts, In Box 4 Added 12/4/84 (Box 4, Folder 3.C.[10] mf 3147:)
  - Subseries D: Futurism, ca. 1910-1954
    - Futurism: General, ca. 1933-1954; 9 items Incl. letter, 3/14/49, "AVF" [Alfred V. Frankenstein] to AHB enclosing letter of 1/11/27 from Benedetta Marinetti of Russolo manifesto (Box 5, Folder 3.D.1 mf 3147:134)
    - "Minor Futurist", 5 items 5 photos: 3 Sironi, 1 Russolo, 1 Rosai (Box 5, Folder 3.D.2 mf 3147:199)
    - Italian show/ Futurist, 1948; 15 items Items in this unit refer to Exh. #413, XXth C. Italian Art, for which AHB wrote futurist section of catalog This unit includes ca. 28+ pgs. AHB's working notes MoMA Lib. call slips JTS [?] n.d. handwritten list on Excelsior [Rome] notepaper of Collezione Marinetti with prices (Box 5, Folder 3.D.3 mf 3147:210)
    - "Balla", 16 items Incl. 1 letter, Balla to AHB, 11/23/48, w. 12 photos annotated on versos 1958 exchange of letters w. Balla's daughter 11 photos, most annotated by MSB (Box 5, Folder 3.D.4 mf 3147:265)
    - Boccioni: Translations of 16 Boccioni letters, 1910-1916; 1910, 1912, 1913, 1915, 1916, n.d. Most to Vico Baer Set of these translations available in Library (Box 5, Folder 3.D.5.a mf 3147:315)
    - Boccioni: 53 photographs, Many dups 1916/17 catalog marked "Benedetta Marinetti" (Box 5, Folder 3.D.5.b mf 3147:345)
    - Carra, 15 items Incl. 17 pgs. of AHB's penciled notes Probably from Carra, La Mia Vita, Rome: Longanesi, 1943 4 pgs. of notes marked "Costantini," probably taken by AHB from Costantini, Vincenzo.Pittura Italiana Contemporanea. Milano: Hoepli, 1932 13 b/w photos (Box 5, Folder 3.D.6 mf 3147:467)
    - Severini, 26 items Incl. 19 pgs. of AHB penciled notes 25 b/w photos Some dups (Box 5, Folder 3.D.7 mf 3147:560)
  - Subseries E: Photographs
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 73 b/w photos Variety of artists and styles Folder labelled by WSL (?) (Box 1, Folder 3.E.1 mf 3147:565)
    - Burden, 8 b/w photos Some dupes (Box 1, Folder 3.E.2 mf 3147:693)
- Series 3a: Barr/Feininger Material, 1927-1944, 1956
  One 10x12x2.5" document box. Series contains correspondence and biographical material regarding Lyonel Feininger (1871-1956) and Alfred H. Barr. Also includes 5 items concerning (Theodor) Lux Feininger (1910-19 ). Received from Margaret S. Barr on February 2, 1978.
  - Subseries A: Lyonel Feininger, 1927-1956
    - Eulogy at Feininger funeral by Alfred H. Barr, Jr., 1/17/1956 (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[1])
    - Further corresp. from Falls Village, 1944; With one letter dated Aug. 29, 1944 With vignette trom Falls Village, black and silver (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[2])
    - L.F. autobiography, 8/1/1944; Typewritten by him Signed and dated in ink 4 pgs., single-spaced (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[3])
    - L.F., his early yrs. in U.S., 7/20/1944; 3 typewritten pgs. Double-spaced Cont. for 2 more pgs. in long-hand Signed Lyonel Felninger, Falls Village (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[4])
    - Catalog of L.F. exh., 3/11-3/29/1941; Buchholz and Willard Galleries, 32 East 57th St. (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[5])
    - 4 photographs by L.F., 3/1929; With view of Bauhaus at Dessau and other places in Dessau (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[6])
    - 2 sheets of reproductions of L.F., ca. 1929; Charcoal drawings (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[7])
    - Corresp. with AHB, 1927-1929; All handwritten 9 sheets contain printed vignettes by Feininger (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[8])
    - Catalog of L.F. exh., Uresden, 2/4/1928 (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[9])
    - 2 photographs of sailboats in the Baltic, Source of inspiration for L.F. work (Box 1, Folder 3a.A.[10])
  - Subseries B: Lux Feininger, 1927, 1928, n.d.
    - Letter, 4/291928 (Box 1, Folder 3a.B.[1])
    - Letter, 12/22/1927; From Dessau (Box 1, Folder 3a.B.[2])
    - 2 clippings, From Das Illustrierte Blatt With reproduced photographs by Lux Feininger showing life at the Bauhaus (Box 1, Folder 3a.B.[3])
    - 1 snapshot, By Lux of his father Signed on back by Lyonel (Box 1, Folder 3a.B.[4])
- Series 4: Foundation for Arts, Religion and Culture (ARC), 1962-1975
  These items shed light on Barr's involvement with and lifelong interest in the relationship between religion and art. Barr was President of ARC from its inception, May 10, 1962, through September 14, 1965. He continued to support ARC activities until ca. 1973. The purpose of ARC as defined in its "Certificate of Incorporation" (See 4.A.10) was "to initiate and foster collaboration between religion and the arts in contemporary life ... " in various ways, such as, through publications or providing grants to individuals. ca. 550 items.
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1962-1975
    Material in this subseries includes correspondence concerning special programs, such as, evening with Robert Motherwell and Friends (see 4.A.6) and William Rubin and Church at Assy lecture (see 4.A.6); fundraising material; invitations; minutes (not marked confidential). Items arranged chronologically.
    - Correspondence, 1975-1971; ca. 25 items (Box 1, Folder 4.A.1 mf 3147:713)
    - Correspondence, 1970; ca. 20 items (Box 1, Folder 4.A.2 mf 3147:795)
    - Correspondence, 1969; ca. 40 items (Box 1, Folder 4.A.3 mf 3147:855)
    - Correspondence, 1968; ca. 70 items (Box 1, Folder 4.A.4 mf 3147:931)
    - Correspondence, 1967; ca. 85 items with Wm. Rubin re: reproducing Gottlieb Blast (Box 1, Folder 4.A.5 mf 3147:1071)
    - Correspondence, 1966; ca. 75 items Includes correspondence re: possible Rubin lecture at MoMA (Box 1, Folder 4.A.6 mf 3147:1248-1340 mf 3148: 4-91)
    - Correspondence, 1965; ca. 80 items Includes fundraising lists and letters (Box 1, Folder 4.A.7a mf 3148:92)
    - Correspondence, 2/5/1965; Evening at MoMA (Box 1, Folder 4.A.7b mf 3148:273)
    - Correspondence, 1964; ca. 35 items (Box 1, Folder 4.A.8 mf 3148:368)
    - Correspondence, 1963; ca. 25 items (Box 1, Folder 4.A.9 mf 3148:470)
    - Correspondence, 1962; ca. 20 items ARC defined - Incorporation statement, etc. (Box 1, Folder 4.A.10 mf 3148:537)
  - Subseries B: Miscellaneous Printed Matter
    - Miscellaneous Printed Matter (Box 1, Folder 4.B.1)
- Series 5: Lectures, Speeches/Talks and Eulogies, 1927-1969
  See mf 3148:595-734. Original order maintained within folders; quotation marks refer to titles and/or annotations in AHB's hand; see Series 1: Personal Correspondence for reference to additional lectures/talks.
  - Subseries A: General Slide Information: Picasso
    - General Slide Information: Picasso, 1960s; See mf 3149:15. Lists included; AHB annotated (Box 1, Folder 5.A.1)